

# CHAMAL FERDINANDUS

**BANKING & FINANCE** 

#### **CAREER OVERVIEW**

I'm a forward looking optimist with a pragmatic mind. I believe experience drive growth and development in which I have excelled myself over the years. I also have developed excellent communication skills and a diligent, conscientious attitude transferable to any modern working environment.

#### ACADEMIC BACKGROUND

BA (Hons) Leadership and Management (2019 -2021) Coventry University UK

Higher Diploma in Business Management (2017 - 2018) NIBM - Sri Lanka

Certificate in Computer Science NIBM - Sri Lanka

G.C.E Advanced Level - 2014

**G.C.E Ordinary Level - 2011** 

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### Banking Assistant - Credit Card Business Union Bank of Colombo PLC| Jan 2019 - Present

- Overall management of credit card sourced by branches and tracking end to end process for processing credit cards sourced by branch.
- Perform pre screening of credit card applications and data enter customer details in bank provided systems.
- Responsible to process card reversals and credit management support to card business team.
- Monitor performance on credit card sourcing branch wise and provide MIS to the relevant senior level managers
- Ensure the branches adhere to processes and instructions introduced on credit card sourcing
- Initiating card business development function

# Trainee Banking Assistant - Card Security & Compliance

Union Bank of Colombo PLC| Sep 2018 - Jan 2019

- Monitor and verify system triggered transactions and take instant decisions within the agreed guidelines in order to minimize losses
- Suggestion / recommendations given to minimize the potential fraud losses and card Centre costs, update necessary logs/ records to maintain a fully-fledged MIS within the department
- Ensure MIS are timely circulated among group/ local stakeholders.

#### **SCHOOL ATTENDED**

Kaluthara Vidyalaya National School (2001-2014)

#### CONTACT

#221, Sedra 03 Building, Al Muteena, Deira, Dubai
T | +971 50 788 7416
E | chamalferdinandus@gmail.com
Linkedin |
http://linkedin.com/in/chamalferdinandus-5305a9200

#### **KEY COMPETENCIES**

- Ability to operate MS Office and MS excel
- Analytical Skills
- Multi Tasker

#### **PERSONAL INFO**

- Date of birth 02-12-1995
- N.I.C Number 953370409V
- Gender Male
- Nationality Sri Lankan

#### REFERENCES

#### **Rizy Amjad**

Fraud Analyst
RAK Bank
No - 219, Binghatti Crystals,
Sllicone Oasis, Dubai
Mobile - +971 58 532 0648
Email - rizy.amjed@gmail.com

## Dananjeyan Wijendra

Chief Manager - Retail Assets Centre Union Bank of Colombo PLC No -64, Galle Road Colombo - 03 Mobile - +94 77 31 14 625 Email - dhananjayanw@unionb.com

- Assisting seniors to set up fraud detection and authorization parameters.
- Investigations done when customer is disputing a fraudulent transaction noted on his/her credit or debit card and taking the necessary.

## Internship Trainee - Corporate Credit Department Bank Of Ceylon | May 2017- Aug 2017

 Handling corporate customer and provide relevant solutions under the close supervision of chief manager - Corporate relationship.

#### **ACHIEVEMENTS**

# **SPORTS**Represented Following Sport

 Member of the Union bank basketball team which emerged championship at the mercantile tournament (2020)